## **Kyle Dixon**

28736 SW Finland Ave Wilsonville, OR 97070 406-270-2174 kldixon406@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/dixonky github.com/dixonky

Recent graduate from Oregon State with a BS in Computer Science. Understanding of and experience working with C#, C, C++, Python, JavaScript, HTML, SQL, and Assembly computer languages. Prior psychological, neurological, and statistical lab experience, including working with and guiding human participants and rodents through experimental procedures. Knowledge of SPSS, MATLAB, and R statistical packages. History teaching and tutoring for classes at an undergraduate level. Experience working at a sub-acute facility for mental health and chemical dependency as well as a residential home for mental health disorders.

## **EDUCATION**

**Bachelor of Science: Computer Science,** Oregon State University- Graduated March 2020, GPA: 3.65 **Master of Science: Psychology,** University of New Mexico- Graduated May 2017, GPA: 4.18 **Bachelor of Arts: Psychology,** Willamette University- Graduated May 2013, GPA: 3.75

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

**TEACHING ASSISTANT**, UNIVERSITY OF NEW MEXICO, ALBUQUERQUE, NM, September 2015- May 2017 https://psych.unm.edu/graduate/index.html

- Designed lessons and substituted for professors, in-person teaching classes of 100+ students.
- Oversaw online and electronic aspects of classes of 1000+ students.

**LAB TECHNICIAN**, UNIVERSITY OF NEW MEXICO-DR. PENTKOWSKI, ALBUQUERQUE, NM, July 2015- May 2017

https://psych.unm.edu/people/faculty/profile/nathan-s.-pentkowski.html

- Specialized in research involving behavioral and neurological outcomes of drug use.
- Designed and conducted experiments including animal (rodent) behavioral and neurological testing.
- Analyzed and reported data using Excel, MatLab, SPSS, and other statistical programs.

**MENTAL HEALTH ASSOCIATE**, LIFEWORKS NW, TIGARD, OR, September 2014- February 2015 http://www.lifeworksnw.org/

- Taught and modeled life skills at a resident home for young adults dealing with mental health and behavioral disorders
- Created, organized, and ran treatment-based events for residents at site and in the local community.
- · Administered daily and PRN medicine to residents.

MENTAL HEALTH SPECIALIST, PATHWAYS TREATMENT CENTER, KALISPELL, MT, October 2013- August 2014

http://www.kalispellregional.org/krmc/behavioral-health/pathways

- Worked with and collaborated as part of a treatment team to provide acute care and counseling for clientele of all ages suffering from chemical dependence and various mental health disorders.
- Developed and led life-skill, wellness recovery action plans (W.R.A.P.), and other therapeutic groups for both adolescent and adult clientele.
- Coordinated with clientele to create and establish safety and further treatment based after-care plans.

**RESEARCH ASSISTANT**, WILLAMETTE UNIVERSITY-DR. MILLER, SALEM, OR, September 2010-May 2013 http://www.willamette.edu/cla/psychology/faculty/miller/

- Developed experiment structure and implementation for multiple psychological research projects.
- Performed experiments on participants with ages ranging from college aged to the elderly.
- Presented findings at a local research conference (Student Research Recognition Day).